<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Spencer Sharp</title>
        <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com</link>
        <description>Your blog description</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 09:51:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Spencer Sharp</title>
            <url>https://sathyanvelumani.com/favicon.ico</url>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2023</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manufacturing need through design – Visit to IKEA]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/manufacturing-need-through-design</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/manufacturing-need-through-design</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes from Service Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finally!!</p>
<p>It was worth the wait.</p>
<p>I had seen the construction of the building for a long time. The branding exercises with the autos were refreshing. All the autos had the IKEA blue. As designers, you understand the value of fonts in design and sometime TYPE is design. But, with IKEA you know it.</p>
<p>Stepping into the theme park
It’s been a long time since, I stepped into a theme park – I even forgot the joy and jubiliation when entering one; the last time would have the school excursion to Dizzee world! I felt the same before entering IKEA, Hyderabad. The circular entrance was still closed and maybe they are on pilot mode still. But, you can clearly see a lot of people walking in, not the best of the entrance experience. It was more like entering a manufacturing shop.</p>
<p>After the security check, a poster suggested that you need the app to shop. I tried installing the app in the store believing that’s necessary to buy in IKEA. Nobody around were installing the app. and soon got distracted by the famous ‘Marius’</p>
<p>Marius stool – it greets you right at the start
Why the stool?
It’s affordable and you can’t add it to your bag yet.
This makes the customer find out the way to buy it. It also forces everyone to understand how to go about exploring the rest in the IKEA big store. At this point, I went to the coworker asking her how to buy the stool? Then, we got the blue trifold leaflet and the showroom map? Experience design!! More about this later</p>
<p>“You can take a photo of the tag. that’s the easiest” – a helpful IKEA co-worker.</p>
<p>Flow chart
At first it was not easy to understand how the shopping works. When did you have a guide to shopping handed over to you at the entrance? Shuffling between the shopper I am and the researcher, It was a confusing state. Again, How do I buy things here?
Yes, I didn’t read paper in my hand, who does when you are trying to buying something.
Everybody is climbing the stairs somewhere. Only when you go there , you realise its a place where you see things that are very different from what you see in you house everyday.</p>
<p>At this point, understand there are different tags and difficult to buy things. No ordinary shopper things about 3 different types of tags and ponders over the shopping experience – but the researcher in me, was very happy!!</p>
<p>Selling the idea
Elaborate room of different sizes furnished with everything a small room can potentially have. This room definitely succeeds in generating a need – and putting the notion that what you have in your house is old wood and is asking for retirement. Getting the user into a different world. Priming has been used for ages in the advertisement world, but IKEA has a new spin to it. It kindles your subconscious and successfully converts every single person who passes the myriad puzzled path into a customer or even an aspirant. There is a urge to buy something, but you can’t get anything in your hands yet. For the impatient, there is a want to move to the place where you can buy something. We ended up picking a rat here. at this point because you only allowed to see and soak into the design
“Priming is a technique whereby exposure to one stimulus influences a response to a subsequent stimulus, without conscious guidance or intention.”</p>
<p>At first, its a bit overwhelming to see a lot of things. Where do you need to go? I asked the coworker, she said just follow the light arrows on the floor. The ‘light arrows’ – why is it not painted on the floor earlier; may be there will be a new path to test later. Why leave a painted mark on the floor – when you can use the light to reflect the light from the top. Everything about the entire experience was thought through and once you got a bit familiar you know what to do.</p>
<p>Again, Marius stool
It is popularly known that the marius stool and the chicken balls are the largest sold items in the shop. So, the popular stool which greets you right in the front is also there in the furniture place. Why break the rule and show it there at the start? It might be about surfacing the relevant information and also telling the potential customer that there are things to buy which are really affordable. I got a red stool and it is INR 399 at the start. And makes you figure out how to traverse through the shop</p>
<p>Event at this point, I still can’t pick the stool. Its available in the self serve portal.</p>
<p>There are around 8-9 spaces [list it down ???] that you</p>
<p>Now, there is a pause. you see the restaurant , after a tired 2 hour run – you need to grab something to eat. but, its full. so we decided to move down and to the stage 2. the market place. It’s a normal store with starting with Kitchen items, the price tag and the design will make sure that you pick a lot of things here.</p>
<p>There are lots of things here. starting with 1,2,3,4,… [put the order here]</p>
<p>wander before going to the stage 2. Market place.</p>
<p>Self-serve experience
And then finally, the EXPERIENCE of the self-serve area, where you pick you furniture. At this point, you have to ponder over you camera images and find which ones you want to fininalize to pick. Location, Rack – yes. its really simple, there are close to 33 racks. Now you realize that its very easy and the entire journey makes clear sense.</p>
<p>And you wonder how can you picks something way up in the top; its easy. you don’t . everything is within your reach. rest of the place you would realize is used for storage.</p>
<p>Questions and answers?
What would be like if there was no – showroom and you went into the market place directly?
You will never realize what you don’t have. But, all showroom’s try to recreate this but IKEA take it to a different level.</p>
<p>Will IKEA have a online app?
They have an app that has all the products, there are plenty of delivery service out there which can deliver the flat packs. Why won’t it be an online superstore. If that happens, that we will buy only the few things that we want. Why would you get a Marius stool when you have the old stool that has been in the home of the last 20 years and still is strong.</p>
<p>Online order
“You will only buy what you want in Online – the scope of me buying more increases with offline shopping” Parkavi</p>
<p>Overall, IKEA is an Experience; It ould be interesting to find out when IKEA moved from furniture store to an experience. DId they look at data; was it a insight from a research deck or was it was a sudden random thought which culminated into what it is today – THE IKEA EXPERIENCE</p>
<p>There are lots of things that builds the IKEA experience, use of paper to jot down the shopping list, 1 metre measuring tape which is available at few places which you use to find if the furniture would fit you house, finding the rack in the self serve area, in case you change your mind, you can leave the stuff just before you go for billing.</p>
<p>And finally,
Ice cream at the end – Yes, you don’t get 10 INR yogurts anymore. But, in IKEA you do. After all the walking around, this is a welcome relief and yes, it’s full</p>
<p>Finally, why did I write about this? Design. Research..</p>
<p>Experience design
makes you wonder how many designers worked on this project. The light arrows, the Marius stool at the storuy, the ad outside showing the chicken balls outside Ikea, the light arrows that can be positioned at whim by altering the frame that reflects. The road inside that’s ideal for uber pick ups. – everything unfolded like a well written screen play.</p>
<p>And the, yellow bag – I missed this one, there is a place where you drop the yellow bags before the marketplace and pick up a trolley.
[Uber screenshot]</p>
<p>Will I use the app to make the list next time? I want to..</p>
<p>Notes:
Somethings which needs more digging
<a href="https://about.ikea.com/en/life-at-home/how-we-work/democratic-design">https://about.ikea.com/en/life-at-home/how-we-work/democratic-design</a>
Democratic Design</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rewriting the cosmOS kernel in Rust]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/rewriting-the-cosmos-kernel-in-rust</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/rewriting-the-cosmos-kernel-in-rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When we released the first version of cosmOS last year, it was written in Go. Go is a wonderful programming language, but it’s been a while since I’ve seen an article on the front page of Hacker News about rewriting some important tool in Go and I see articles on there about rewriting things in Rust every single week.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When we released the first version of cosmOS last year, it was written in Go. Go is a wonderful programming language with a lot of benefits, but it’s been a while since I’ve seen an article on the front page of Hacker News about rewriting some important tool in Go and I see articles on there about rewriting things in Rust every single week.</p>
<pre class="language-rust"><code class="language-rust"><span class="token keyword">use</span> <span class="token namespace">ferris_says<span class="token punctuation">::</span></span>say<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token keyword">use</span> <span class="token namespace">std<span class="token punctuation">::</span>io<span class="token punctuation">::</span></span><span class="token punctuation">{</span>stdout<span class="token punctuation">,</span> <span class="token class-name">BufWriter</span><span class="token punctuation">}</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>

<span class="token keyword">fn</span> <span class="token function-definition function">main</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span> <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
    <span class="token keyword">let</span> stdout <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token function">stdout</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    <span class="token keyword">let</span> message <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token class-name">String</span><span class="token punctuation">::</span><span class="token function">from</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token string">&quot;Hello fellow hackers&quot;</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    <span class="token keyword">let</span> width <span class="token operator">=</span> message<span class="token punctuation">.</span><span class="token function">chars</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">.</span><span class="token function">count</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>

    <span class="token keyword">let</span> <span class="token keyword">mut</span> writer <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token class-name">BufWriter</span><span class="token punctuation">::</span><span class="token function">new</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>stdout<span class="token punctuation">.</span><span class="token function">lock</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    <span class="token function">say</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>message<span class="token punctuation">.</span><span class="token function">as_bytes</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">,</span> width<span class="token punctuation">,</span> <span class="token operator">&amp;</span><span class="token keyword">mut</span> writer<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">.</span><span class="token function">unwrap</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token punctuation">}</span>
</code></pre>
<p>I derive a large amount of my self-worth from whether or not Hacker News is impressed with the work I&#x27;m doing, so when I realized this, I cancelled all of our existing projects and started migrating everything to Rust immediately.</p>
<h2>Sermone fata</h2>
<p>Lorem markdownum, bracchia in redibam! Terque unda puppi nec, linguae posterior
in utraque respicere candidus Mimasque formae; quae conantem cervice. Parcite
variatus, redolentia adeunt. Tyrioque dies, naufraga sua adit partibus celanda
torquere temptata, erit maneat et ramos, <a href="#">iam</a> ait dominari
potitus! Tibi litora matremque fumantia condi radicibus opusque.</p>
<p>Deus feram verumque, fecit, ira tamen, terras per alienae victum. Mutantur
levitate quas ubi arcum ripas oculos abest. Adest <a href="#">commissaque
victae</a> in gemitus nectareis ire diva
dotibus ora, et findi huic invenit; fatis? Fractaque dare superinposita
nimiumque simulatoremque sanguine, at voce aestibus diu! Quid veterum hausit tu
nil utinam paternos ima, commentaque.</p>
<pre class="language-c"><code class="language-c">exbibyte_wins <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token function">gigahertz</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token number">3</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
grayscaleUtilityClient <span class="token operator">=</span> control_uat<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
pcmciaHibernate <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token function">oop_virus_console</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>text_mountain<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token keyword">if</span> <span class="token punctuation">(</span>stateWaisFirewire <span class="token operator">&gt;=</span> <span class="token operator">-</span><span class="token number">2</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span> <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
    jfs <span class="token operator">=</span> <span class="token number">647065</span> <span class="token operator">/</span> <span class="token function">ldapVrml</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>tutorialRestore<span class="token punctuation">,</span> <span class="token number">85</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    metal_runtime_parse <span class="token operator">=</span> roomComputingResolution <span class="token operator">-</span> toolbarUpload <span class="token operator">+</span>
            ipx_nvram_open<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token punctuation">}</span> <span class="token keyword">else</span> <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
    maximizeSidebar <span class="token operator">*=</span> <span class="token function">suffix_url</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>flatbed <span class="token operator">+</span> <span class="token number">2</span><span class="token punctuation">,</span> requirements_encoding_node <span class="token operator">+</span>
            only_qbe_media<span class="token punctuation">,</span> minicomputer<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token punctuation">}</span>
</code></pre>
<p>Aere repetiti cognataque natus. Habebat vela solutis saepe munus nondum adhuc
oscula nomina pignora corpus deserat.</p>
<h2>Lethaei Pindumve me quae dinumerat Pavor</h2>
<p>Idem se saxa fata pollentibus geminos; quos pedibus. Est urnis Herses omnes nec
divite: et ille illa furit sim verbis Cyllenius.</p>
<ol>
<li>Captus inpleverunt collo</li>
<li>Nec nam placebant</li>
<li>Siquos vulgus</li>
<li>Dictis carissime fugae</li>
<li>A tacitos nulla viginti</li>
</ol>
<p>Ungues fistula annoso, ille addit linoque motatque uberior verso
<a href="#">rubuerunt</a> confine desuetaque. <em>Sanguine</em> anteit
emerguntque expugnacior est pennas iniqui ecce <strong>haeret</strong> genus: peiora imagine
fossas Cephisos formosa! Refugitque amata <a href="#">refelli</a>
supplex. Summa brevis vetuere tenebas, hostes vetantis, suppressit, arreptum
regna. Postquam conpescit iuvenis habet corpus, et erratica, perdere, tot mota
ars talis.</p>
<pre class="language-c"><code class="language-c">digital<span class="token punctuation">.</span>webcam_dual_frequency <span class="token operator">=</span> webmasterMms<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token keyword">if</span> <span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token number">5</span> <span class="token operator">+</span> language_standalone_google<span class="token punctuation">)</span> <span class="token punctuation">{</span>
    cc_inbox_layout <span class="token operator">*=</span> file_character<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    task <span class="token operator">+=</span> p<span class="token punctuation">;</span>
    lockUnicode <span class="token operator">+=</span> <span class="token function">enterprise_monochrome</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>tokenFunctionPersonal<span class="token punctuation">,</span> keyVirtual<span class="token punctuation">,</span>
            adf<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
<span class="token punctuation">}</span>
<span class="token function">windows_binary_esports</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token number">87734</span><span class="token punctuation">,</span> <span class="token function">array</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span>restoreRomTopology<span class="token punctuation">,</span> <span class="token function">adRaw</span><span class="token punctuation">(</span><span class="token number">407314</span><span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">,</span>
        dongleBashThumbnail<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">,</span> interpreter<span class="token punctuation">)</span><span class="token punctuation">;</span>
</code></pre>
<p>Sit volat naturam; motu Cancri. Erat pro simul quae valuit quoque timorem quam
proelia: illo patrio <em>esse summus</em>, enim sua serpentibus, Hyleusque. Est coniuge
recuso; refert Coroniden ignotos manat, adfectu.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Quest for Patterns in Online Roulette]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/the-quest-for-patterns-in-online-roulette</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/the-quest-for-patterns-in-online-roulette</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes from Service Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A friend, who firmly believes in the element of randomness in everyday life and is always on the lookout for patterns, tried his hand at online roulette. This was the perfect opportunity to test his theory that it&#x27;s possible to find patterns in the numbers and exploit them to win. The established casino in Colombo provided a live stream of their roulette, making it an ideal setup to analyze the numbers.</p>
<p>Using Excel and the =randnumber() formula, we started our experiment. The first spin resulted in 36, which was on my list. He wanted 11 numbers instead of 10, so we agreed and I added another number. To our surprise, the adjacent number was 19, which I won.</p>
<p>However, after a few rounds, he seemed to have figured out the spins and the differences between them. Despite having a random selection of 12 numbers and him having 12 carefully picked numbers, nobody won and it was a draw. The spinner changed, and he said &quot;I like this female spinner,&quot; but that didn&#x27;t guarantee him a win in the next 5 rounds. After 15 rounds, he was losing 7-4 and wanted to play another 5 rounds.</p>
<p>He said &quot;This is not a game of luck,&quot; but after 18 rounds, the score was 9-5 in his favor. However, the spinner changed and he lost 8-7. The problem was that the random number generation seemed to repeat. So, we switched to using an iPad to identify patterns. Betters often wait until they identify a streak and continue to bet until they lose it.</p>
<p>Finally, we settled down with an iPad and pencil to mark the patterns and see if it works. To our surprise, it did seem to work. But, isn&#x27;t it always the case that we see patterns all the time?</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is User Journey is the most powerful service design tool?]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/user-journey</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/user-journey</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes from Service Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year marks the completion of 2 years working in the mAgri project. A good point to reflect on what was done and how things were done. mAgri gave me an opportunity to work in Sri Lanka on a very interesting and successful product.</p>
<p>GoviMithuru/Ulavarthozhan - Dialog
[Write about the product]</p>
<p>User journey example</p>
<p>Why User journey works:</p>
<ol>
<li>It forces the team to think about the touch points that exist. This acknowledgment and putting it together in the linear forces us to think differently in silos. Marketing is not just worried about the first two parts of the design, it becomes everybody&#x27;s responsibility to understand what is being done and how it impacts the product design work.</li>
<li>When it is combined with PIW - Product Iteration Workshops, which we had every 3 months after the initial launch ensured the same set of people got to the problem and stayed connected with the product development process - this reduces the need to sell ideas hard and the biases when it comes from the top down. Most of the answers came from the Field Research - I have spent close to 70-80 days in the field during the two-year tenure</li>
</ol>
<p>At the end of the project, I gave a Research Workshop where the team where keen to take the good job forward and really understood the benefits of user journey and thinking about Systems then siloed projects.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GSMA mAgri Design Toolkit]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/gsma-mAgri-design-toolkit</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/gsma-mAgri-design-toolkit</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Contributed to the Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The mAgri Design Toolkit is a collection of instructions, tools, and stories to help develop and scale mobile agriculture products by applying a user-centered design approach.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/magri-design-toolkit">http://www.gsma.com/mobilefordevelopment/magri-design-toolkit</a></p>
<p>I started working on the mAgri project as UX Consultant for Dialog mAgri Product, Sri Lanka. The project is live in 6 countries Sri Lanka, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Myanmar, Ghana and Malawi.</p>
<p>A lot of our learnings have been compiled in this amazing toolkit by GSMA and Frog. The toolkit from GSMA is divided into 6 useful modules – Intro to UCD, Plan, Learn, Create, Develop and Maintain,  and will come handy for  anyone who is working on a mobile product for the BoP. The case studies and tools used go beyond mobile Agriculture.</p>
<p>Happy learning!!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maasai Mara - Photo Essay]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/katchatheevu–our-unplanned-trip</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/katchatheevu–our-unplanned-trip</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes from Service Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maasai Mara</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[???]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/katchatheevu-trip</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/katchatheevu-trip</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Notes from Service Design]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>???</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kargi Road Station]]></title>
            <link>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/kargi-road-station</link>
            <guid>https://sathyanvelumani.com/articles/kargi-road-station</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When you’re building a website for a company as ambitious as Planetaria, you need to make an impression. I wanted people to visit our website and see animations that looked more realistic than reality itself.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kargi Road Station, is one of the smallest of the railway stations where the passing train won&#x27;t ever stop for more than 2 mins. I was on a visit to the JSS, Ganiyari to understand more about the In Patient Module and CHW(Community Health Worker) module and was on my way to Shivtarai sub-center to understand.</p>
<p>To know more about what i do <a href="http://sathyanvelumani.com/about-me/" title="About me" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a></p>
<p>This being my second visit JSS ended up shorter than originally planned and was ready to leave on  train on 5th, Utkal Expresss from Bilaspur RAilway station to New Delhi.</p>
<p>IRCTC.co.in with alexa traffic rank 441, , is always down. I have never been successful in booking tatkal tickets online ever. I had decided that i would go to the Kargi Road Station, with the assumption that it would be empty and i would  be successful in getting the ticket. I reached the station exactly 11 am when tatkal booking starts(starts 10 am in bigger stations such as Bilaspur) , and was the first in the queue. The man in the counter would have been around 45 years old wearing a nicely pressed white shirt , comfortably sititng showing that he had everything he needed to get the job done.</p>
<p>His first attempt to log in into the railway network failed, cursing the gods, he called his colleague and figured out what needs to be done to get the system working again. It was the usual. Manual shutdown by holding the power button and kicking the system back on. The system was on now, and he started running around looking for something in all the registers around the table. After 5 mins, he found what he was looking for, the login id and password. He tried logging in to the system for 7-8 times, by now, he had another person assisting him.</p>
<p>By this time, the queue got bigger and bigger and i had my work team coming from the hospital in a jeep to pick me enroute to the subcenter. I suggested that he check the CAPSLOCK , if it was on by mistake. It was. Few in the queue showered short praises for the thought and i was again hoping to get my tickets. My first tatkal ticket, was a near dream now; he calls his friend now to tell him that the system is back working. Surely an achievement for the day, 2 mins goes away. When he came to my form after completing couple of cancellations, which could have been done later. The  waiting list for 3AC and Sleeper were now 5 and 16. And when he tried booking, the system didn&#x27;t let him do it. The jeep came and i had to leave.</p>
<p>I did end up getting on the train the next day, which was 2 hours late; Got into the sleeper, and found a comfortable place near the door of S7, spent 6 hours sitting and sleeping before paying the extra fare and got a sleeper berth to spend the next 18 odd hours thinking about the interface which didn&#x27;t tell the user that CAPSLOCK was ON and the service provider who took his own sweet time and didn&#x27;t realize that time was what he had that day and the customer&#x27;s didn&#x27;t.</p>
<p>It was an experience. Kargi Road STation, i realized is one of the most beautiful stations i have ever been to. With a small grass covered hill on one side and a small station with a single counter. The super fast trains don&#x27;t stop, but Utkal express from bilaspur did stop there on my way to New delhi.</p>
<p>Next time, i visit JSS hospital, i have decieded to spend a good sunday afternoon on the railways station and may be climb the small hill for some pictures of the station</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>spencer@planetaria.tech (Spencer Sharp)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>